James L. Pool

(925) 922-7426 | 1256 Bond Street, San Luis Obispo, CA 93405 | <u>i.levin.pool@gmail.com</u>

Professional Summary

Motivated Software Developer seeks employment as part of a dynamic software development team. Fluent in C, C++, HTML, and JavaScript with extensive experience in Python and Java. Other notable skills include:

- Good communication and listening skills
- Strong analytical and problem solving abilities
- Excellent leader and team player

Education

Corvallis, OR

Oregon State University

June 2015 – August 2016

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, August 2016; GPA: 3.9

Mobile & Cloud Software Development | Computer Networks | Web Development | Database Design Software Engineering | Operating Systems | Analysis of Algorithms | Usability Engineering

San Luis Obispo, CA California Polytechnic State University July 2003 – June 2008 Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering / Mechatronics Concentration, June 2008; GPA 3.2 Control Systems | Heat Transfer | Mechatronics | Robotics | Mechanical Vibrations | Thermodynamics

Employment

Acrylic Cutter & Fabricator

TAP Plastics

June 2015 – June 2016

- Cut Acrylic, Polycarbonate, HDPE, and ABS plastic sheets
- Custom fabrication of simple to moderate complexity pieces
- Interact with customers and assist with sales
- Equipment: Table saw, drill press, heat bender, router, sanders

Mechanical Engineer

Northrop Grumman

March 2013 – June 2015

Marine Systems – Propulsion & Power Generation

- Develop, improve, and maintain Magnetic Bearing Analysis Software
- Lead engineer for Turbine-Generator dynamic behavior modeling
- Assisted in demonstration of Advanced Control Features on existing platforms
- Assisted with trouble-shooting Magnetic Bearing Engineering Model test platform

Robotics Instructor

Athenian School Summer Camp

Summer 2012

• LEGO Robotics Instructor for Grades 4-6, responsible for curriculum design and all teaching

Mechanical Engineer

Naval Surface Warfare Center

Sept. 2008 – Dec. 2011

Combat Systems Support Equipment Engineering Branch

- Performed on-site Material Condition Assessments on topside Fire Control Systems
- On-site representative and Quality Assurance for phased-array radar coating application
- Fabricated antenna and radome composite moisture standards
- Developed Testing Procedures for Non-Destructive Polymer Cleaning Pads
- Updated branch training materials and official response messages

Mechanical Engineer, Intern Panasonic Avionics Corporation

- In-Flight Video Entertainment System Hardware Design Group
- Prototyping & Assembly of Engineering Design Models
- Test Support & Documentation: Thermal Chamber & Vibration Shake-Table
- Technical Drawing Updates: Aluminum Sheet Metal and Electronic Cable Design

Technology Summary

Summers 2005 & 2006

C, C++, HTML, Java, JavaScript, Python, SQL & VBA Node.js, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Cloud9, Google App Engine, Android Studio Pro/Engineer, SolidWorks, MATLAB & Simulink